[Music]
w
W hello and welcome everybody to this
slightly delayed episode of the ask
visit Show episode 189 I hope you're all
doing great so so let's see as always uh
who all is there on the live stream with
us before we get into anything I can see
designer life jant geopolitical du DHA
AR arush harit Singh vishak Meg tanay
desand praka Joi vinit Yash tiari sual
ban Bora knowledge Seeker vun Singh
Malik GK abai abijit Gupta chak ombe
Kiker hello Prashant Kumar akiles Sam
Satish abijit ring Niara again Som
rakasi Raj a kavri Raa Ain asor hello t
n j Vishnu mohanan threat Ripper red
sidar AB p singla s designer life swick
nobody you know tanay Pand Mr Carrot
samidi Gojo red Prashant Kumar harap
Singh rakit the pod life Akash Dar
anurag Bish Sharma AC rishikesh Das
Gupta mlin gupta's educational Channel
DJ surj push vinit
Raul um foram prianka Niara akiles
mp uh t b
Sadam anol
ragal ataj TR patil hello American
cheese hello
uh and everybody else okay okay so uh
we're gonna okay let's take a few more
Tommy verti J thing just need sing Ram
Karma darak aradhya and aan ishan minini
Priyanka T and everybody else okay okay
let's let's stop greeting everyone at
this point so once again thank you
everybody for being in the live stream
apologies for the slightly delayed live
stream I was in Delhi yesterday I was at
rashti ban attending the swearing in
ceremony of prime minister modi's thirdd
term and his cabinet and it all is
thanks to you thanks to your viewership
thanks to the numbers that I have all
because of you and I represented you
over there so gratitude and a tremendous
amount of thanks to all of you for
making this
possible all right so once again I'm
going to take a bunch of questions from
the comments I'm going to answer 15 20
of those and then I will take question
questions from the live chat once those
questions are exhausted so it's going to
be a hybrid session not all the
questions are be going to be from the
comments I'll take your live stream live
chat questions also at at the end I mean
in the second half of this episode so
let's see who all and and for and also
let me thank those of you who
congratulated me for being invited to
the swearing in ceremony I can't answer
each of you individually but thank thank
you to each and every one of you I
really appreciate that okay let us take
questions all right let's take question
one where is it okay here it is it is by
Arijit
bannery the question is terrorist attack
on Hindu pilgrims in Kashmir 10 killed
40 injured till now terrorism has had
decreased by 95% under Modi 2.0 but
right now at the beginning of Modi 3.0
we had such a big attack
do you think that terrorism will Peak
again in Modi 3.0 as now Modi G is a
weak prime minister with less power I
don't think so look I it's true that
it's no longer a BJP government this is
now an NDA government the BJP is of
right now doesn't have a full majority
they need the support external support
or internal support of other NDA allies
which gives a lot of
power in the hands of those parties uh
the telm the rjd uh I I think it's Mr
nsh Kumar's party and so all so even
though these parties have a small number
of seat it gives them a tremendous
amount of power you could say
disproportionate power but you can see
that the yesterday the swearing in
ceremony happened and you can see the
people who are sworn in the ministers
and Ministers of State Etc who has sworn
in you will see that the majority of
those are still
BJP uh
MPS and all the major important
portfolios will still be handled by the
BJP so it's not like even it's not like
because these external NDA allies have
this leverage that they can get away
with anything and eventually it is quite
possible that the BJP may cross the 272
273 Mark by absorbing other independent
candidates or candidates from MPS from
other parties into the BJP that may
happen and the BJP May by itself cross
the 273 halfway Mark in Parliament that
may happen in the next few months I mean
lots of speculation about that it's
entirely possible it may happen and if
that once that happens if that happens
then the BJP is entirely strong enough
on its own so I don't think it's going
to be a very weak BJP
government uh Mr Modi right now is uh
kind of weaker than what he was during
the past two terms slightly diminished
power but I don't think it's going to
change much from the perspective of
foreign policy from the perspective of
Economic Policy from the perspective of
anti-terrorism policy so what does this
attack this terrorist attack on Hindu
pilgrims in Kashmir mean it means that
foreign powers I mean look this
terrorism in Kashmir is entirely a
foreign cre creation it's a phenomenon
that has been phenomenon that has been
funded and financed for decades by
external Powers we see we think of it as
a Pakistani creation no Pakistan is a
proxy
it is the United States that funded and
financed Pakistani terrorism in India
for decades during the second during the
first cold war in the 20th
century and today well Pakistan is still
a vasal of the US and to some extent of
China I mean they they would like to
counterbalance the US with China but
overall it it is still very much a wasal
of the US okay and so if something
happens in India Pakistani terrorism
we've got to understand that there are
reasons behind that and the the the West
would like to see India cut down to size
India has been very assertive the past
10 years of Mr modi's government and
they would like to cut you
know cut that down to
size so one can see this what happened
in that context it doesn't mean see look
you can't catch all the fish there's
always going to be some terrorists who
get through and do things so at the very
start of Mr modi's third term this is an
attempt to put pressure on his
government to pressure put pressure on
him
to make him look weak to make India look
weak and so on but I don't think
terrorism will will make a comeback in
Modi 3.0 I don't think so at all and if
if the pakistanis try any tricks then I
I think then I think we know what
happens one second I think we have a
problem with the with the
sound one second give me a second let me
uh give me a second
okay so uh is the sound fine now is it
fine now the sound I think there was
some issue with the sound yes I think it
is clear it is clear
now okay I think it it it was clear
before also so I'll just
continue the way I was going
okay so we have to understand the
Pakistani terrorism in that context if
the pakistanis try any real trick
they're going to see that India will
respond very robustly and maybe they
will get a reaction that they despite
the balakot and other things they still
may not expect so I don't think the
pakistanis will try too much of this so
yeah that's that's my that's my opinion
that's the way I see it I don't see
Pakistani terrorism making any comeback
in India they will try something they
may try to push their luck here and
there but overall it's not going to work
for them and if they if they cross a
certain line if they they try too much
it's going to come to bite them in the
them in a in a way that they may not
have
expected okay pray Paul says Prime
Minister Modi has said he's here for the
next 10 years do you see any reason to
be optimistic or Yogi should be there in
2029 as per your postelection podcast
statement people definitely are
delighted but what's your deep rooted
opinion on this if he wins the majority
mandate again then how do you see Yogi's
future position from the context of
serving bat okay look I am very clear
first of all um look uh I wanted Mr Modi
to come back to Power I've been saying
this for a very long time and I'm very
happy I'm delighted clearly I mean if
you recall
uh uh I I had this podcast on I had a
podcast with ran some time ago about a
month or so ago and this is what I had
said and it was recorded before that so
it's very I was very absolutely clear
crystal here I want to see Mr Modi come
back to Power you can call me whatever
you want it doesn't make any difference
to me and I have certainly
got got what I wanted
so so uh very much uh Mr Modi comes back
to Power that's what I wanted and I have
got what I wanted now the question is
I'm not sure if mod has Mr Modi has said
that he going to be here for the next 10
years I don't think if I'm not sure at
least I personally don't remember don't
recall hearing him say that that he's
going to be there for the next 10 years
I know that he had said uh sometime last
year that he that he will be the Prime
Minister candidate for the third term
and he did that and he he has been
reelected
he's he is once again the prime minister
of India continuing the third term I
don't recall him making the statement
that he wants to be there for the next
10 years
I think the way I see it this probably
is the final prime minister term for Mr
Modi obviously at the end of the day
it's entirely his choice and if the
people still vote for him they they
still Repose their faith in him then
absolutely fine but the way I see it he
is u in the by the time this term ends
he's going to be in the mid or late 70s
and I think that's reasonably that's a
reasonably good time for a leader to
pass on the beton to the next generation
of leadership that's how I see it
obviously at the end of the day it's
entirely his choice but I would like to
see a leader like Mr Yogi be the Prime
Minister Prime ministerial candidate in
2029 uh so that's how I see it the deepr
rooted opinion on this is I don't know
my opinion is that Mr Modi I would like
to see him perform tremendously well
during the next 5 years and then I would
like to see on the next next generation
of leadership uh coming to the four and
as of today I see Mr Yogi Yogi adiat G
as the right next leader from the BJP
perspective that's how I see it uh so Mr
Yogi obviously will have to perform
he'll have to do a tremendous job
continue to do a tremendous job in uttar
Pradesh elections will will come up he
will have to win those then it'll be a
hattick for him so he was appointed
chief minister sometime into 20 which
whatever the second decade of the 20 of
the 21st century then he won an
election and or did he win the election
okay whatever happens he has to win the
next elections and he has to continue to
do a tremendous job in up and then he
can if he does that then he has
certainly proven his his credentials as
a leader of up the most populous St in
India and that would bolster uh his his
his chances of becoming the next prime
ministerial candidate so that's how I
see
it next
question okay this is by
Haley okay the Lo SAA election result is
out last time you expressed
disappointment to Mr Modi for leaving
out a lot of important tasks in his
initiative look he has done a tremendous
job I think Mr Modi has been the best
prime minister we've had in India since
1947 okay
he has been the best prime minister
we've had since 1947 and after he became
the Prime Minister we started hoping and
we started really believing that India
can be a great power in the century
people even believe that he's going to
be a super power it's entirely because
of Mr Modi when Mr manm Singh was there
nobody was talking about this so Mr Modi
is the best prime minister we've had and
he's proven that in the next past 10
years of course I have been disappointed
with the with the fact that the
education system hasn't been reformed
nothing has been done about culture and
civilization nothing not not enough has
been done from the cultural and
civilizational
perspective the illegal infiltrators
have not been thrown out whether they
are ringas or Bangladesh's or whatever
else and so on so yes no matter how well
a prime minister performs there's going
to be something that there's going to be
scope for improvement so yes and I
obviously have been disappointed with
the fact that the education system and
so on so forth has not been uh nothing
nothing not much has been done education
nothing has been done and so on now the
question is about Manipur right uh the
BJP lost both seats to the Congress in
my little state of Manipur too yes the
BJP lost both the state both the seats
in Manipur loksabha seats to the
Congress yes as a m I'm extremely
frustrated with Mr modi's inaction and
non- intervention to reduce the crisis
uh to resolve the crisis fast like
thousands lacks of Other M manipu who
voted against him so let me explain
something before I take on the rest of
the
question there's only one political
party that is in a position to
eventually resolve the the Manipur
problem right and in their wisdom the
mes of Manipur have voted against that
political party and they have voted for
the political party that has caused the
problem I would like to applaud the
wisdom of the people of Manipur of the
mes you have have voted for the
political party that has created the
crisis in the past 70 years and before
that also and then you want the party
against whom you voted to resolve your
problems what incredible wisdom my
friends now my I would like to ask you
do you want me to tell you things that
that you will like to hear that you will
enjoy hearing or do you want me to tell
you the
truth the truth is not always Pleasant
to hear but I think you need to hear the
truth
you're extremely frustrated with Mr
modi's inaction non- intervention to
reduce resolve the crisis fast we put
your faith in him by electing BJP which
still holds the state government but are
thoroughly disappointed with his by his
unacknowledgement of the crisis and the
deteriorating condition of the state how
do you think he will now act with regard
to Manipur now that he he has been
reelected under the NDA Alliance do you
see the N partners and the stronger
opposition push him into action or will
he just sit on it all like the last time
listen if Mr Modi had just been sitting
and do you think the infal valley would
be safe
today huh do you know the numerical
disparity between the the cookie
population and the M
population do you think infal Valley
would be safe if if Mr Modi had done
nothing now the question you are right
Mr Modi has not spoken about Manipur
right he has not spoken about
Manipur why is that let me explain why
first of all let's understand what this
problem is H and who who is to blame for
this problem is Mr Modi to blame is the
BJP to blame for this
problem this problem is that of
industrial scale illegal immigration of
foreigners into Manipur into India right
when did this begin my
friends when did this begin it began in
the 19th century after 1891 when Manipur
lost its sovereignty to the British
after the Ang manipuri War so Manipur
loses its sovereignty and then the
British start and even before that the
British had started bringing in
Outsiders into Manipur to punish to to
to uh create an artificial balance of
power which never existed so before the
British came into the picture after the
great king Ching Tang Kumba died rajar
bhandra what a wonderful King he was he
did so much for culture but he is the
cause of the loss of sovereignty of
Manipur he did not take care of of
National Security he was busy doing
culture which is great he did not even
ensure that he the right succession
happens and then there after he dies
without a clear Su succession path all
his sons fight each other and Manipur
becomes weak which is why the burmes can
invade the burmes invade Manipur and
then there is seven years of Devastation
and then in the early 20 19th
century yeah early 19th century the
British get involved and that's where
the sovereignty problem begins in
Manipur so the root cause is your King
bhandra by the way who is revered as
rajar bhandra but he he ruined your
National Security when Manipur was still
a nation Kingdom so the British get
involved then they start bringing in
foreigners event initially slowly slowly
then the Anglo Manipur War happens 1891
Manipur loses then the mes are forcibly
confined to the infal valley and large
scale cookie influx happens starts even
in 1901 the cookies were less than 1% of
the population but then the British
began industrial scale influx of cookies
into Manipur to to punish the mes now
after 1949 when Manipur becomes a part
of India did the mate
people raise anything any any voice
against the cookie
infiltration no there was Insurgency all
across the Far East of India Northeast
the Naga Insurgency the Miso Insurgency
the bordo Insurgency the Manipur
Insurgency everybody was fighting these
insurgencies because the Far East of
India was marginalized by the congress
party by Mr neu's government and success
of governments but the m is never raised
they were not even aware of the fact
that they have been marginalized so
badly and the cookies have taken over
the entire south of Manipur the nagas
were aware they fought the cookies m is
quiet until May last year you people
were not even raising your voice you
were living
happily now May May 3 or whatever it was
2023 happens and then you are raising
this issue which is a very legitimate
problem obviously you you're facing a
problem but why were you not aware of
this that your land has been taken
over and you did not even just living
blissfully and completely unaware just
living a happy life because you have
your little part of Manipur into which
you have been forcibly confined no
nobody was Raising this issue of the
illegal cocain infiltration now you you
are blaming the BJP for
it really is the BJ BJP to blame who
ruined Manipur in the 20th century after
1949 you have voted for that political
party
and you know I have done many podcasts
on my channel there's only one or two
that I
regret okay and The Honorable MP that
you have elected said that doing that
podcast with him is something I regret
and let me make a prediction for you my
dear mate friends the next 5 years The
Honorable MP that you have
elected is going to do nothing for
Manipur
okay that's a prediction I'm making
right now watch this video again in 5
years I think you will only learn
through
pain so that's what now why has Mr Modi
been quiet is the question right this is
a geopolitical issue the British
brought in cookies into Manipur before
they came in before the British were
were involved there were no cookies in
Manipur the British brought in C in
Manipur after 1891 even more so the
Indian go the nehruvian government and
later 20th century governments of India
also brought in more cookies and you mes
were quiet you did not raise a
single uh you did not raise the issue at
all maybe you were not even aware of
what's happening
right
so and so and then in the 21st century
right now there's a civil war situation
in
Burma and this cookie influx that's
happening now in the past few years past
decade or so that is actually geopolitic
issue geopolitical issue to to pile on
more pressure and pain on India and of
course the mes they are still the only
large scale surviving Hindu population
even though there are people among the
methes who don't who claim not to be
Hindu and there are like two three laks
who have converted to Christianity but
still the ma are predominantly still
Hindu or polytheistic so that also is a
problem right so Western Powers want to
destroy that they want to convert the
entire far east of India into a
Christian region and then they can
create more separatism because once you
convert to an abrahamic religion you
develop extra territorial extral
loyalties that is something that there
is a pattern you see throughout history
in China and Japan
everywhere so this is a geopolitical
issue if and and the root cause of the
issue is the presence of lacks of
illegal foreigners who have infiltrated
into India now if Mr Modi speaks about
this it gives an opportunity to the
foreign powers to to call him a fascist
and take various actions against him so
you don't speak about it but you take
the actions now there is no solution to
the Manipur problem which is going to
happen in the next six weeks or six
months or even six years the problem has
been created over a
century maybe more so do you expect a
solution in 3 weeks or one year it's
going to take minimum 20 years to solve
the problem and if the Maes had raised
their voice 50 years ago when the
problem already existed then maybe it
would have been solved by now and it's
not the fault of the mes you people are
very
innocent very innocent people not aware
of what's happening in the world and not
aware of how the world works and the
innocence is is very clearly
demonstrated by the person you have
voted into power as an
MP so listen there is a difference
between words and
actions Mr Modi I know it is I'm sure
it's very hurtful that Mr Modi has not
spoken about Manipur there's a reason
for it at least he's taking some action
that you may not even be aware of I know
there are
problems I know I know what the problems
are but it's going to take time to
resolve the issue there are leg these
these ISS these issues these problems
are Legacy issues and Legacy
problems many things need to be done
better of course it's going to take time
so right now there's nothing there's no
short-term solution to this absolutely
none it's going to take a minimum of 20
years to solve the problem if the mes
had raised their voice 50 years ago when
the problem already existed maybe it
could have been solved by now but no
didn't happen so what can I
say okay mlan says uh why don't other
nations respect India even small Nations
like the Maldives Bhutan in Nepal try to
bully us sometimes I think Indians are
too
soft okay let's talk about respect and
let's talk about bullying do you know
the meaning of bullying
sir bullying is when a cowardly large
strong person picks on somebody who
can't fight
back okay that's called bullying which
means that the person who is doing the
bullying is larger than the victim
typically generally or stronger than the
Vic victim and they know that this
victim is somebody who can't fight back
maybe this victim has no friends is an
unpopular
kid is a loner and so on so forth so you
pick on a weak person and you bully that
person you and you bully that person
that's called that's called bullying you
don't pick on somebody who's bigger and
stronger than you bullies are cowards
even though they're strong so now so
that is bullying okay so when the
Maldives does something against India
when Bhutan does something Nepal does
but something it's not bullying by the
way it's not bullying at all it's called
opportunism
now now the main question is about
respect now so let me ask you a
question here you see a cat a kitty cat
here you see a
tiger which one will you
respect you see the kitty cat you'll say
oh how cute perhaps if you like cats you
see the tiger whether you like cats or
not you will say oh I'm to stay as far
away as
possible
okay so you see a little puppy dug puppy
dog you see how cute here is a puppy dog
here in this hand here I show you a bear
a Himalayan brown bear you see you see
the puppy dog you say oh how cute you
see the Himalayan brown bear you'll say
I'll go to the next state I'll not go in
Jammu and Kashmir or lak I'll go to
Punjab or I'll go to Delhi I won't be
there so you you don't respect a puppy
you don't respect a cat or a kitten you
respect the tiger you respect the bear
you respect the elephant you respect the
crocodile you respect the python the
Anaconda you don't respect a goldfish
you respect a shark where does respect
come from my dear
friends respect comes from
Fear mostly at least in the world of
geopolitics respect comes from fear in
the world of civil societies you respect
people of course we in India have a
whole ancient culture we respect those
who are learned we respect those who are
cultured and so on but in the world of
geopolitics which is not Indian culture
it is global culture respect comes from
brute force from brute strength it comes
from
fear in
geopolitics the rule of the Jungle
applies okay
now I haven't cracked open the map to
have I so let's crack crack open the map
and let's look at respect from a map
from a map
perspective
now here's the
map here's a map so this is the Indian
subcontinent and the surrounding regions
right so apart from China the largest
country in the region is obviously bat
it is India Maldives is not even visible
Nepal obviously we know where Nepal is
Bhutan is this smaller Nation here and
so on now just from the perspective of
size do you think these little Nations
can bully India no right and India in
the past 10 years has become such a
large economy the the fastest growing
economy and a much stronger Nation
there's no question of these nations
bullying it India then the question
is so in
Asia there's only two Nations that are
really from the perspective of other
nations
uh worthy of
respect and of course you need you need
to have the willingness to use the power
that you have so it's India and China
and to some extent Iran in Asia that's
the Nations that would potentially scare
other nations of course India is not a
hegemonic nation so other nations are
aren't really scared of India but the
fact that India is so large such a large
economy such a large population a
powerful military and the nuclear
weapons that obviously
brings a certain amount of respect
automatically so what does let's talk
about the Maldives as an example and
then Nepal also right the Maldives has
been uh they have this India out
campaign H and uh they they asked India
to take back whatever military personnel
we had a few 100 or so military
personnel and they're bringing in
Chinese companies and asking Indian
companies to leave for their
infrastructure projects do you call this
bullying this is not bullying it's
opportunism so they know that in the
current geopolitical scenario India is
not going to turn up tomorrow morning
with a bunch of naval ships because
there are other more powerful nations in
India like the US which won't allow this
to happen forget about China the
Americans won't allow India to arm twist
the Maldives because the US wants to
contain India and of course China is
also a major power the Maldives can the
if you understand the geopolitical
scenario the balance of power and all
that then you can play one nation
against another nation and that's what
the maldis are
doing they are playing India against the
US and
China that's what they're doing okay and
of course there's a cultural thing
religious thing that's why they are
antagonistic towards India and then they
use these things to to offset India
using the leverage from other nations
when it comes to Nepal
Nepal was never anti India it was one of
the Indian governments one of The Indian
regimes in the 20th century that ended
the nepales monarchy and
actually supported the
maoists and that's how the maoists have
become a major political force in Nepal
and the maist appr China so the that
Indian government brought in a class of
politicians in Nepal and they brought
them to power who are anti- India and
pro-china and imagine the stupidity the
abject idsy of
that and why because Nepal was a Hindu
Nation Nepal was a Hindu rashtra so to
destroy Hinduism in Nepal and now
there's a big large scale Christian and
other conversions happening in Nepal now
by the way so to destroy Hinduism in
Nepal and to destroy the Hindu monarchy
and the Hindu rra stat of Nepal they
brought in an anti India and prchina
Island kind of governments we had in
India okay
so now today in in in Nepal if you all
these parties are I mean all these
maoist and leftist communist Etc parties
are anti- India and today the nepales
mindset I believe many of the nepales
especially the youngsters have become
kind of
anti-india and when you are anti-india
and then you will obviously want to
offset India by cting China so once
again it is just playing one nation
against another there's no bullying in
this there's no bullying in this and
Bhutan is an even smaller
nation and the Chinese are nibbling away
at BH bhan territory they at least
trying to do that they they're claiming
bhutan's territory as their own and they
would like to use this pressure to turn
Bhutan into a pro-china anti-india
nation and so on so that's what's
happening okay all these nations it's
not like they don't respect India it's
just that they know that India is weaker
than China China whether you like it or
not is about four times more powerful
than India overall hard power so they
use this against India so what's the
solution it's not that Indians are too
soft and India is too soft it's just a
fact of nature that China is more
powerful than India and smaller Nations
will try to play One Nation against
another that's just how the game of
geopolitics is played so it's not India
is too soft it's just India hasn't risen
enough thus far India needs to grow more
India needs to become A1 trillion
economy let's touch $5 trillion first
then 10 it's a long game it's a it's a
long it's it's a something it's a
long-term game that we are playing
there's no short-term solutions to this
the only solution is for India to regain
its historical position as the world's
largest economy historically India was
the world's largest economy for most of
History we need to regain that position
then respect will come
automatically next question herel
says despite the Maldives government's
anti-india stance we still invited the
president Mr muu to the swearing in
ceremony yesterday what could be the
reason behind this move as we did not
invite anyone from the temporary Nation
Pakistan and Afghanistan too okay what's
the reason behind this move it was not
an invitation it was a
summons India summoned Mr muu and told
him
come come and and pay respect to
our Democratic process come and pay your
respects we summoned him and he came
that's what it was it was not an
honorable invitation it was not us
extending an honor of course you you
invite somebody to the swearing in
ceremony you're extending a great honor
to them but it was not just that it was
also a summons you come and you pay your
respects that's what it actually was
okay so I know lots of Indians are upset
that we invited Mr muuu who is so
anti-india to the swearing in ceremony
no it was actually in a sense a show of
strength also reminding them that at the
end of the day you in our neighborhood
you're in our backyard and you better
behave yeah we know that you you're
you're cting China and so on so forth
but just let's let me just remind you
guys who's the real uh big fish in the
neighborhood so it was a summons for Mr
muu he was uh he was told to come and to
pay his respects and he did that and he
will portray it as an honor that see
they respect me so much that they
invited
me wasn't that and if if you were I was
there yesterday at this wearing in
ceremony and Mr when Mr mizu's name was
announced a lot of significant portion
of the crowd was booing him the audience
there was an audience of about 10,000
people significant portion was booing
him which was undiplomatic but these
that's the audience that's not Indian
Diplomat so all
right so it's it's uh clearly evident
that more Indians are now aware of
international relations and geopolitics
earlier earlier for most Indians
the word geopolitics did not exist in
India first of all and international
relations and Foreign Affairs meant
Pakistan and Pakistan only nothing else
but now Indians are more aware of other
things like smaller Nations like the
males and so on so forth and so for Mr
muu it was a summon okay he was
essentially told to come and pay his
respects now why didn't we invite the
temporary Nation because it doesn't
matter the temporary Nation Pakistan is
a temporary Nation we why why should we
invite people from a temporary Nation
that's a terrorist regime right and
their leader is not even a leader the
real Force the real power in Pakistan is
the arm for is the Army the
military so if we invite a puppet prime
minister who is not really in power
what's the point of doing that and
secondly why should we engage with these
terrorists who are anyway temporary
Nation so Mr modi's policy is to
completely ignore Pakistan which is the
right policy so that was this was just a
continuation of that when it comes to
Afghanistan the Taliban is
well the Taliban also have been
installed in power okay they haven't uh
won an election that's fine you don't
win an election but they haven't even
conquered the country the country was
given to them on a plate by the
Americans and the
Americans uh allegedly pay the Taliban a
stipend which is between 50 to 100
million a week as claimed by various
reli reasonably reliable sources now we
have good relations with with the
Taliban but we officially haven't uh
recognize the government as the
legitimate government in Afghanistan but
unofficially we have reasonably good
positive relations with the Taliban
and eventually it could go in a even
more robust Direction so at this point
in time it was not appropriate to uh
invite any Taliban
representative I did see some people who
I thought were Taliban but clearly I was
wrong oh there so we have invited the
Taliban
okay Shan says China has
deployed advanced fighter jets the j20
or their alleged fifth generation
fighter plane so theyve depl deployed
these advanced fighter jets uh near Sim
and other parts of the in of the Indian
border with Chinese occupied Tibet are
they up to something big near the
borders near the borders the Chinese are
ramping up their infr infrastructure
building efforts and their uh military
muscle north of the India of India's
border with Tibet so in the Tibet
occupied occupied Tibet region near the
Indian border the Chinese are ramping up
their their activi ities military
activities they're ramping up building
more roads and infrastructure they're
building tunnels and and and bases under
the mountains because they know that
they're very exposed with they're very
visible if India if there's a war India
can launch missile strikes and wipe out
significant amounts of Chinese uh
military Assets in the region because
it's
just there's no Forest cover there
there's nowhere to HDE it so they are
building they're digging tunnels under
under the mountains and digging bases
under the mountains in Tibet in occupied
Tibet and they are bolstering their
military muscle in the region which
means bringing bringing in more military
assets like these fighter planes and all
that what's the point what's the purpose
of all this maybe they're planning to go
to war with India it's a
possibility we have
to understand that a war with China is a
possibility it may happen it will happen
if the Chinese desire of war and India's
economy is going to keep on growing
Modi 3.0 I don't expect any changes so
India is going to become more and more
of a challenge to the Chinese from their
perspective we don't claim Tibet as our
territory we have actually officially
recognized Tibet as a part as a part of
China the great Mr vaj did that official
recognition of T Tibet as a part of
China but the Chinese understand what
power is and the more powerful a nation
becomes that power is like a force which
acts outwards it's like a pressure that
comes in so uh the Chinese are very
practical and they fear India they
pretend to not fear India but they
actually
do and uh Mr Modi is a very different
kind of prime minister so they they
actually are worried about uh the rise
of India so it is certainly possible we
have to keep this in mind you to be
aware of this that there could be a war
between India and China in the next
coming coming who knows when could
happen it it is possible maybe a war is
going to
come so maybe they are doing
preparations for that so what needs to
happen from India's perspective India
needs to I think take almost emergency
measures in the next two three years to
build up our military muscle we need to
have tremendous stores of
ammunition we need to have 10,000 plus
missiles
stockpiled 20 brahmos and 50 this will
not work
see what's happening in Ukraine Russia
why is Russia prevailing because they
have seemingly inexhaustible stores of
ammunition they don't have inexus stores
of ammunition their factories are
working overnight 24 by7 to churn out
the ammunition needed to sustain a long
War so we have to heed the lessons of
Ukraine so India needs to take almost
emergency measures now in my opinion to
ramp up India's ammunition stock piles
and various kinds of
weapons um I would say we need way more
artillery we need to significantly
bolster our Naval strength because the
key to making China behave in the
Himalayan region in the T occupied Tibet
region actually lies in the Indian Ocean
region
counterintuitively okay you can do
various things in the Indian Ocean to
make the Chinese behave up
north uh so India needs to do that
it is I think quite possible that the
Chinese May at some point in time in the
next few years decide to wage a war
against India and
uh humiliate
India humiliate the Indian leadership if
they
win and to end the Indian growth
story so a war I think it's possible
maybe even likely in the next few years
and maybe this all this buildup they're
doing as the military buildup and all
that maybe it is in preparation for that
war so I think India needs to be really
proactive and ensure that if there's a
war it first of all it should not be a
long War it should be a short war and we
should have the the wherewithal the
military wherewithall to take the battle
to take the war to their territory to
the territory they occupy in Tibet
that's what needs to
happen next question
is okay let's try and bring the question
in okay let's take another question if
that one doesn't come up okay this is
one second what was the previous
question okay this is by RIT
akand Bharat has been the heartland of
our dharmic culture 2,000 years ago our
ancestors gifted Hinduism and Buddhism
to the people of Southeast Asia but
after all this time the remaining
dharmic Southeast Asian Nations seem to
have preserved Our dharmic Heritage much
much better than us despite being the
majority why didn't we preserve and
nurture Our dhic Heritage and culture
listen we fought for our heritage in
culture we have been occupied by
colonizers abrahamic
colonizers for a significant portion of
the past Millennium Thousand Years not
the whole of bat not the whole of India
but various portions at various points
in time so we had the turkey occupation
of India which began about a thousand or
so years ago and it lasted until the
Turco M mugal Empire existed and it was
the maratas that that destroyed the mul
Empire the tur mugal
Empire and then the maratas were brought
down by the European by the British so
you had two major phases of foreign
occupation one was the both were
abrahamic in nature but two different
religions so India
resisted
throughout and India was very much
dharmic until the British
left and then we were made to believe
that after 1947 we had an Indian
government and we were now ruled by our
own people so we became complacent and
what happened what turned out is that
the people who were ruling us after 1947
were even more
adharmic than the British and because we
had become complacent we went along with
everything and the education system
remained the same the institutions
remained the same as in the British
colonial institutions everything
remained the same even today nothing not
much has changed the Constitution is a
foreign abrahamic Constitution there's
nothing dhic about it the education
system is entirely alien it is nothing
but a continuation of the 19th century
British colonial education system and so
on so generation after generation after
generation multiple generations of
Indians have gone through the education
system and what the education system
does is that it upoos it it deines
Indians it's India is the only nation
where the education system doesn't teach
children their own culture their own
history so you grow up having no
connection with your culture and history
and your parents are so busy trying to
earn a little bit of money that they
don't have the time to take care of you
and
so you are not really that much in sync
with your parents you spend less time
with your parents than as compared to
with your teachers and then when this
happens over several Generations people
and we end up where we are today that
most people have connection to Indian
culture they don't they see it as
something almost alien to them why do we
need this why do we need a temple why
don't we have a school
there why don't we have a
hospital and so
on so that's where India has ended up
now a completely deracinated secular
Nation where most kids and most adults
hate their own or are ashamed of their
own culture they don't see any value in
that they see it as something that
belong to the past and it should be
relegated to the past we have to become
more modern which means more
Western and whatever is the in thing
today is what we will pretend to follow
so that's what's happened to India
that's why I've been so frustrated with
nothing being done to to reform the
education
system it's a long-term
problem now these nations the Southeast
Asian Nations uh you have Thailand soomi
Myanmar Cambodia Malaysia Indonesia will
not talk about even Indonesia even
though it's a Muslim country it still is
more it still uh respects its Hindu
Heritage more than India respects its
own Hindu Heritage and so on so even a
nation like Vietnam which is officially
a communist nation is more dharmic today
even today more more in touch with its
dhic Heritage than India is today so
it's it's because of the dharmic erosion
that's been
engineered understand engineered dharmic
erosion
we have been systematically cut off from
our roots and today if you speak about
Hinduism these 17 year olds and 12 year
olds they will they'll make fun of you
they'll say haha why do we need this
nonsense and then they will have a list
of 15 reasons that they've been taught
why to hate
Hinduism and then we have political
parties with the media they're all in
sync with this anti-hindu narrative
India is the most hinduphobic nation in
the
world India is a nation that practices
anti-hindu apoide
so it's all by Design it's all been
engineered by the British and they left
a bunch of people in power in 1947 who
were entirely in synchronicity with that
agenda I mean what happened to the fire
East the northeast of India after 1947
it was christianized after
1947 this was engine this was
demographic and religious re-engineering
done by the government of India post
1947 yeah and yeah obviously the vector
agent was American missionaries and so
on but Baptists and whatever else and
today the people of that
region okay very nice people actually
innocent very innocent people but they
hate their own ancestral culture that's
what this
does so those of you who have any
connection with your own culture cherish
it and fight for it and we our ancestors
fought for it but we are not fighting
for it that's where we are today in in
free allegedly free
India so it's going to be a long process
a long road ahead of
us okay sorab has a couple of questions
one second where are we yeah sorab has a
couple of questions s boria uh why
didn't we study in detail about the
contributions of Indians in mathematics
compared to what we studied about the
Western contributions in our Academia
isn't our education system responsible
for creating an inferiority complex do
they want us to be mentally enslaved and
secondly one of the previous year's upsc
questions stated that Akbar wanted to
unite the
nation uh like Ashok did but Maharana
pratab was a terrorist who became a
hurdle in Ash in in akbar's path and in
his Noble quest to unify the nation yeah
so these questions both these questions
are about the education system the upsc
is an extension of the education system
and uh yeah so
yeah the first question is about
mathematics India is the birthplace of
mathematics
India has given more contributions to
mathematics than anybody else all modern
mathematics exists on a foundation of
Indian mathematics but no one knows
about it's completely being erased first
by the Europeans and then by the
mentally colonized Indian slavish Indian
academics and the objective is to ensure
that Indians don't realize that what
their ancestors contributed to
mathematics and science so that we
continue to have this inferiority
complex and the inferiority complex is
perpetuated it is strengthened and we
are taught that everything came from
outside which means we there is no value
or worth in
ourselves so the objective is to
mentally enslave Indians it's to create
an inferiority complex and it's succeed
bril brilliantly most Indians have an
inferiority complex most Indians if an
Indian person says something they'll say
oh it's nonsense if an Indian person
writes a book or an article they they'll
poo poo it they'll laugh at it but if an
Indian gets validation from the west
then that person becomes automatically a
hero so that's the inferiority complex
of the Indians they think that white
skin is superior to brown skin and they
think that a foreign accent is superior
to an Indian accent this is all done by
the education system by by teaching
falsehoods and lies and omiting
censoring lots and lots and lots
tremendous amounts of pertinent
information that you should know about
your heritage so the the objective is to
mentally enslave Indians and it works
brilliantly most Indians you will see
have a deep rooted inferiority complex a
deep sense of Shame about their culture
and they can't imagine they can't
believe that anything good comes out
comes out of India and the object of
this is to uh reform Society reform
society means to appro Hinduism destroy
Hinduism and bring in one of the two
major abrahamic religions in its place
that's the objective very
simple so the education
system doesn't it doesn't teach you how
to think it teaches you what to think it
doesn't teach you how to ask questions
how to ask the right questions which
means formulating a problem properly it
just tells you to absorb to swallow
whatever nonsense is put in front front
of you and so on now the other thing is
about the upsc question Akbar wants to
un the nation and all that Akbar was a
foreigner it doesn't matter whether he
was born in India
he
and terrorist Maharana was a terrorist
do you know what Akbar did in
chorar 30,000 men women and children
were were Massac in one day at the
orders of Akbar isn't that terrorism
Akbar was a terrorist
okay but the upsc and all the upsc
preparation materials and all if you go
through that it's going to make you a
self-loathing
person ridden with an inferiority
complex and once you clear the upsc exam
what do you become you become an is
officer right that's the problem we are
facing there are still some good is
officers I'm sure there are many good is
officers but I also the majority are in
are are are mentally
colonized and much of the Hindu phobia
that's prevalent in India comes from
there so the objective is to destroy
India as a society that's the briti
that's that was the objective of the
British when they created the education
system and we have continued that and we
are still continuing that and that is
one of my greatest frustrations that Mr
Modi had 10 years Modi 1 Modi 2 in which
to make some changes some new education
policy has come out which addresses none
of the root issues none of the major
root causes of the problems the major
structural issues addresses nothing it's
a it's mostly
cosmetic
so I don't know will something happen
this this this fiveyear term I don't
know okay bnu says doesn't democracy
have its own benefits that dictatorship
or monarchy doesn't have for example
people can vote out the leader they
didn't like as opposed to in a
dictatorship or monarchy where change is
Messier and harder and may require
civilians fighting an armed government
you said India must eventually go back
to its hybrid system what would that
look like in the modern context Kings
and princes or like Russia or China and
what would be the way to build the
system organically and how long it may
take for India
okay democracy versus
dictatorship imagine
okay
democracy has its
benefits dictatorship also can have
benefits which is
better
so imagine you have a dictator like Paul
po Paul po the guy who ruled
Cambodia he killed off maybe two million
of his country people
completely innocent people children men
women for what reason I don't know what
I know what but communism if you have a
dictator like that what do you do the
people can't even fight because he's
starving them all so it it it took
another Nation to intervene Vietnam
right so that's the danger of
dictatorship now what kind of
dictatorship was I talking about
monarchy monarchy is dictatorship isn't
it now in what context does the monarchy
exist is the question dictatorship so
when it comes to Mr Xi Jinping you can
call him a dictator or you could call
him an emperor it's the same thing it
doesn't matter the words are different
the the the fact is the same a dictator
is a monarch it's a king or an emperor
or a king is a dictator it's the same
thing so it's not two different things
dictatorship SL monarchy it's the same
thing it's authoritarian rule but in
what context what cultural context does
it exist is the main question so
historically in India we had a hybrid
system like I've said we had a monarch
or Emperor at the top
and then you would have at the
local Grassroots level you would have
people electing their own people their
own governance thing and all counselors
whatever so you're a hybrid system but
at the top you had a dharmic dictator
understand
that and that dictator would have a
council of ministers and so on who would
guide him the Monarch would have that
and they had the right to ask him to
step down if he was not uh doing a good
job and obviously there could be a power
struggle and tussle and all that but
historically if you look at the past
2,000 or so years of Indian history have
you had any King in the past 2,000 years
who was brutal and dictatorial towards
the towards his subjects towards the
people he served or ruled over give me
one name yeah I'll tell you what miul
was bad so miul was a was an immigrant
he was a hon and he was despised by
everyone because he was evil so when but
he was not a dictator in the dhic
context he was not yet Hindu right he
was a descendant of Huns he was a hun he
was he was a first generation Invader
but his Descendants the second third
generation Huns were entirely
dharmic I mean brahmagupta the great
astronomer math mathematician
brahmagupta his Patron was
vagram who was allegedly apparently
Huna second generation or
whatever so so the point is uh you
cannot I hardly can name single King in
the past 2,000 years who was despotic
and brutal towards his
subjects you go back a few thousand
years there's the story of k k Mama
right he was evil but we know what
happened to him he was brought down by
Shri Krish
so the point is if you are operating a
dictatorship in a dharmic context then
it's very hard for you to be oppressive
the culture and the civilizational uh
values take over so at at most at worst
you're going to be incompetent but you w
be
oppressive so if there are the right
kinds of checks and balance and we we've
lost the the the the information about
exactly what the system was like we
obviously have the arastra in which I
mean you can see the checks and balances
that that an emperor has on him the
duties of an emperor he's more like a
like a like a servant of the people than
as an emperor you
know so that's how it was so as long as
it's it's a dharmic system you won't
have
oppression uh now the question is India
should eventually go back to its hybrid
system what would it look like in the
modern context imagine Emperor ashoke
who was slightly naughty obviously he
was kind of brutal but overall he was
good for the country
overall but
imagine kanishka or or or imagine
chhatrapati shivaji
mahaj okay but imagine him with the 21st
century context with all the technology
and everything at his disposal that's
what he would have that's what it would
look like okay not Kings and Prince yeah
that sort of
thing but not like Russia or China
Russia obviously today you can say Mr
Putin is a dictator but he is a dictator
in a Civ in a certain civilizational
context which is the Russian
civilizational context which is Russian
Orthodox Christian context and obviously
it's it's different from the Communist
context which we had in during the USSR
days in the Chinese system Mr xinping
is more in a towest or confusion context
than a dhic context because China has
given up Dharma today and they are more
of a legalist system which is like a
toist thing
yeah and what would be the best way to
do build to build this organically how
long will it take I don't I can't say
the major impediment well lots of
impediments okay so major changes would
need to happen for that to happen in
India
okay Indian persan couple says how do
you see the India Iran relationship in
the future I think Indian personi couple
is YouTube channel let me check it
out let me put that on the screen one
second Indian
Persian
couple okay this is a YouTube channel it
is uh yeah these are the videos so go
check them out my viewers if you are
interested looks like travel
videos most beautiful island in the
world hormos Island B Abbas Iranian
girls day out exploring Iranian Village
Mall in
tan
um Intercultural couple I'm glad they're
saying Intercultural couple not
interracial because India Iran is not
really interracial it's Intercultural
for sure and so on so it looks like an
interesting channel I may watch if I get
the time but the question let's go back
to the question how do you see the India
Iran relationship in the future I think
the India Iran relationship in the
future will be like your relationship
India person couple very good harmonious
relationship look India and Persia have
had a very ancient relationship going
back at least I don't know a few few
Millennia uh Persia is at least 3,000
years old the oldest Dynasty that we
know of is the hak shamish dynasty the
Ain Dynasty which go back goes back
about 1,000 BC and their ancestors were
the Parra people um who were one of the
rigvedic clans of rigvedic India the
parwa clan they are one of the Clans
that lost the battle of the 10 plus
Kings and the ones who lost were
expelled out of India went into Exile
and that's how they settled Central Asia
and the par clan went westwards and
settled Iran so that's that's a story
I've said this many many times uh the
India Persia relationship can be great
in the future right now the major
impediment is the West the West
hates Iran because of
1979 what happened in
1979 uh the hostage crisis and the expel
expelling of the Sha of Iran who was a
us stouge who was and so on and so so uh
and that's why India and Iran don't have
a great relationship in I mean Iran is
right next door from India's perspective
uh major major source of of oil and gas
and that should be our primary sourcing
point isn't it for India why do we need
to get oil from Russia or some Far Over
Place why not from our neighbors in Iran
in Persia but the Americans won't let
that won't let that happen so it's kind
of a missed opportunity not our fault
not Iran's fault it's the Americans who
are meddling in the future I would like
to see the India Persia India Iran
relationship go get stronger
better and historically we've had the
best of relations until at least until
Iran became occupied by the by the Turks
so we all know about the invasion of
India by nadara and most Indians think
of it as the Iranians invading India
nadash sha was not Iranian he was not
Persian he was turkic okay so I don't
blame it on the Persian people or the on
the people of Persia so I think
historically we've had the best of
relations I think in the future I think
the future looks bright and I hope the
relationship goes from strength to
strength in the future there's no need
why it should not and eventually India
and Persia will reconnect bya a common
border eventually it will happen so the
current uh Pakistan Iran Border is the
historical India Persia border so it
will again in the future once the
temporary Nation uh
goes takes its natural course India and
Persia will have a border common border
again the right right now the situation
is an aberration historical aberation
but it'll go back to the way it should
be soon and I would like to see the
India persa relationship uh go from
strength to strength I see no reason why
it should
not okay two questions by RIT sarar
first was slavery present in the Indian
subcontinent before the Turk occupation
of India and secondly I've come come
across certain information that says
that chhatrapati shivaji Maharaj
abolished slavery from India in 1645
what which made him the first king in
the world to abolish slavery how far is
this true and what's your take on this
okay
so was slavery present in the
subcontinent of India in the Indian
subcontinent before the turkey
occupation of India the answer is very
simple no there was no slavery in India
before the Turk occupation of India or
the Turk presence in
India to many any evidence hard evidence
I mean the Greeks were here the Greeks
India had uh excellent relations with
the Greeks during the morian era the
Greeks have written about India mastan
wrote about India in this book Inda he
says he said very clearly the Indians
don't believe in slavery there's no
there are no slaves in
India um and some wonderful erudite
historians have Tri have tried to claim
that the word Dasa means slave
slave well that's not what Dasa means
Dasa means
servant
okay servant like public servant or
whatever servant a servant is somebody
who serves it doesn't mean
slave but some historians like The Usual
Suspects have tried to claim that Das in
slave so that's obviously a lie there's
no I mean it's clearly a lie complete
lie so there was no slavery in India
before the turkic occupation of India
and there are people who claim that
there was slavery in India right they
are the ones who are referring to the
turkic occupation phas of India and they
tury occupiers as Indians like or was
Indian hm Akbar was Indian these people
had
slaves what balban gas balban yeah he
belonged to the slave Dynasty right
buban the mamluk dynasty these were
turkic slaves not Indian slaves so
Indian Kings never had slaves now this
information that chhatrapati Shar
shivaji Maharaj abolished slavery in
India at whatever date I don't know
about this date but maybe it's
right what does it mean does it mean
that Indians were practicing slavery and
he had to intervene and and abolish
slavery no it means that he liberated
territories from the
Turks and the Turks were practicing
slavery there and chhatrapati shivaji
Maharaj abolished the slavery in the
regions he had liberated that's what he
means he had abolished this ghastly
brutal barbaric malpractice that had
come from outside
India so that's what it
means so does it make him the first king
in the world to abolish slavery Maybe
but it was not Indian slavery abolished
it was Turkey slavery that he abolished
I'm glad he did great man great
king okay R SAR again why isn't Delhi
very well developed compared to Capital
Cities like Bangkok quala lumur Jakarta
Istanbul and all of these cities are
from developing countries what are my
thoughts okay let's let's talk in a more
General sense broader sense let's not
talk about Delhi let's talk about Indian
cities you take the average Indian city
you're right that if you compare Delhi
with Bangkok Etc it's not that well
developed but if you take the average
Indian city large large Metropolitan
City let's a million plus population or
let's say 100,000 plus population the
average Indian city and you compare that
with the average city of a similar size
in Thailand
Malaysia turkey Etc you will see that
the Indian City are are less developed
they are worse to live in why is that so
let's take a hypothetical large Indian
city I will not take any name it is a
hypothetical large Indian city could be
any City I'm sure there are many cities
which are not like this but let's take a
hypothetical large Indian city what and
you go there what will you see take a
satellite image okay you go to a map
Google map and you open the satellite
view what do you see
okay in this hypothetical unnamed Indian
city which could be in any part of
India you will
see large
pockets of
slums
slums Hut
hutments illegal slums on public
property on on public land and these
slums will exist for some time for a few
years and then they'll become
regularized because in this high
hypothetical unnamed Indian city in any
part of India the local part politicians
will regularize Islam what what does it
do and and where does the slum come from
so in the past people who lived in the
rural parts of India had to migrate to
large cities any city in India large
city to get employment because the rural
parts of India were marginalized and
neglected today it is less so so where
do this slum dwellers come from in this
hypothetical unnamed Indian city where
do they come
from most of them are Bangladesh's and
ringas okay so why are these Bangladeshi
and ringas allowed to settle in these
places in this hypothetical Indian city
by these hypothetical local politicians
why because it's a vote
Banks you settle Bangladesh is there you
allow and we know that when they enter
India from wherever they enter they get
AAR cards and everything which means
they can get election IDs done on the
basis of the other card which means they
become citizens
illegally right and then they are
settled in Islams they're allowed to do
whatever they
do and they become vote bags for the
local politicians in these hypothetical
unnamed Indian cities I'm sure there are
cities that don't have this okay I'm not
saying all cities are like this by no
means but there will be cities like
this and when these rag tag illegal
infiltrators come and settle down in
your city what happens it places a huge
burden on the Civic services on the
amenities on everything on the economy
of the city and it brings down the
quality of the
population and the neighborhoods become
unsafe right so that is one problem and
then in these hypothetical unnamed
cities I'm sure there are good good
place also but in many of these places
the politicians are deeply corrupt and
whatever funding is allocated per year
for the for the municipality or whatever
much of it
is much of it is not used for the
purpose it was allocated for and there
are lots of means of doing that
allegedly and so on so the root cause my
dear friends is
corruption today we are fortunate that
we we have a government at the center
that is not corrupt we are really
fortunate Mr Modi has ensured this but
at the lower levels Grassroots level of
India everything is corrupt not
everywhere I'm sure there are places
where it's not there but generally you
find it more likely than not to see
corruption so these are the problems I
would when are we going to see a war
against
corruption that is what's holding India
back the major thing that is holding
India back ISR
coruption so I don't know about Delhi
what the situation is like I I don't
live in Delhi I'm not very familiar with
Delhi but I am saying without naming any
specific City overall you will find
something like this more likely than not
I'm sure I'm sure there are cities that
don't have this problem but I'm sure
there are some cities that also have
this problem so that's one example of
what is wrong in India in overall the
root cause of everything that's wrong in
India is
corruption so that's what needs to be
tackled but that is not a small battle
that is a gigantic War because the
entire system some people would say runs
on corruption so what do you do about
that rodit sarar again is it true that
diplomacy and secularism was born after
the Treaty of West faia
1648 or is this European
propaganda okay so the Europeans will
would like to you to believe that before
before the
Europeans appeared on the world stage
there was no diplomacy there was no
secularism there was no civilization
there was nothing everything good came
out of
Europe right
now so West failure is uh 1648 right
when did Henry VII live let's go to our
friend Google and Google Henry
VII uh Google
okay this is Google Henry
8 so Henry VI e lived in between 159 in
1547 okay 1509 to
so this guy so let's understand what
secularism is secularism
means um the distinction it means that
the church it means separation of the
church in the state that's what
secularism means today in the Indian
context it means destroying Hinduism in
the Indian context secularism means
destroying or attempting to destroy
Hinduism the native culture of India in
India only but globally historically
secularism has meant the separation of
church and state
because in the first Millennium ad the
Roman Empire was transformed at least in
the western part into the church Empire
the Vatican Empire and the popes were
the real Emperors of Europe and they
meddled in everything kings and queens
and Emperors in Europe were vasal of the
popes okay so the Pope the church was
the supreme authority in everything now
Henry VII who lived before the Treaty of
West faia he had a
problem he was married to this lady
called Katherine of on very Pious lady
very nice lady who was much loved by the
people of England she was
Spanish but she was not able to produce
a male child for Henry VI e and Henry
had become in infatuated with this other
lady uh anain and he wanted to divorce
Katherine and he wanted to marry an
bolain and he had to beg the pope to
allow this because he couldn't even get
a Wars without the approval of the Pope
and the pope refused to give this
approval so then what Henry did is that
he separated church and
state by uh by revoking his allegiance
to the to the Vatican and creating the
Anglican
Church that's what he did so he
separated of course he did not entirely
separate church and state because uh he
kept certain powers he dissolved all the
monasteries in England and took over all
their possession and all their wealth
and all their lands so he kind of
usurped many of the powers that the
church had so this is before the Treaty
of West failure it's not entirely
secularism but he cut the church down to
size and brought in a kind of church the
Anglican
church and before Christianity even
existed there was no church and state so
it was all
secularism and look you can't really if
you look at the us today they say in God
we trust it's only now in the late 20 in
the late 2010s that they have actually
marginalized the church and become an
atheistic and non-Christian Nation but
historically it was always in God with
in in God with
trust so the us whether you like it or
not was a Christian Nation until very
recently so where was the different
where was the secularism in the US when
it comes to the UK do you think it's a
secular country it's a Christian Nation
many European nations are officially
Christian nations
so secularism is is just a myth okay so
it it was there well before the Treaty
of best what about diplomacy was there
diplomacy before the Treaty of bestest
failure when Lord Krishna tried to avert
war between the pandas and the and the
cors what was he
doing he went to the cors and off and
said that we will the pandas are willing
to accept just five Villages so that
there's no War what was that was that
not diplomacy but you'll say hey the
Mahabharat is a myth Lord Krishna is a
mythical figure that's what you will say
many of you at least some of you my
viewers are not that stupid but yeah
okay let's say let's not talk about the
Mahabharat in
the which year was
this Chandra Gupta Mor's lifetime okay
Chandra Gupta with the help of his
mentor vishnugupta these the two of them
they defeat the nand
Dynasty and uh Chandra Gupta becomes the
Emperor of
India then so there is the beginning of
the morian Dynasty in bhat in India then
Alexander dies and his generals all
fight each other they go to war the war
of the deoki
deai and the strongest of his generals
Salas
nikator uh comes to say hello to IND so
there is a brief war between the IND
between India and and the macedonians
between the Greeks the sald morian war
it lasts about a year or two it's not
very serious and then the two sides
negotiate a
peace and it is said that one of the
peace terms was that Chandra Gupta would
marry a daughter of ccas so that there
are family relations between between the
two sides and then there is no chance of
War whether that happened or not we
don't know for sure but there there was
diplomacy there was a peace agreement
ccas gave back whatever he had taken the
entire Gandhara region
Afghanistan so India got all those
regions back and Chandra Gupta gave ccas
500 war elephants with the pilots the
Mah mahs and using that
massive
uh military muscle so Lucas was able to
carve out a great Empire for himself so
wasn't that diplomacy
and the diplomatic relations were so
great that even after ccas died and
Chandra Gupta died their sons had
extremely friendly warm and cordial
relations with each other and that's
known so that's diplomacy so listen the
Europeans will claim everything good
came from there but we don't have to
believe that nonsense right we have
evidence to the contrary they'll say
mathematics came from Europe astronomy
came from Europe science came from
Europe they did not even know how to add
large numbers but yeah mathematics came
from Europe blah blah
blah okay why why says the hunas or the
Huns the sakas or the skians the taras
or the tarians who are most likely
tarians are mentioned in the Mahabharat
as M tribes of Northern and Northwestern
India correct does this suggest that
they were they are of Indian origin
rather than turkey or Iranian origin
okay the suckers the shakas the
skians were most likely of Indian origin
your historians in jnu ETC and western
western historians will say that the
skians were an iranic ethnic group
iranic yeah we know for a fact that the
skians invaded India fleeing from the
toar from the from the kushans about
2,100 years before today they invaded
India successfully they set up Kingdoms
in India and then they slowly culated
into into India and there is not
one record that says there was any
ethnic or cultural Clash or Strife
between the PE between the Indians and
the
skians we know the skians were
polytheist who worshiped the skun the
sun we know their language is classified
as iranic which means it is very similar
to Indian languages so overall the
skians one can
say and we know that there were lots of
uh migrations out of India the past
2,000 years starting from the Battle of
the 10 Kings maybe before that also so
the whole of Central Asia was settled by
Indian origin kingdoms who slowly became
culturally different from India so the
skians and even the tarians taras or
kushans were descendants of ancient
Indians the hunas well the Mahabharata
hunas may be different from the Hun the
show knew of of two and a half thousand
years before today maybe and the ones
who invaded India who tried invading
India during the Gupta
era so the Mahabharata Huns may be
different from those Huns but what so
the main question is mchas right what
does mcha
mean so from the Indian cultural
perspective civilizational perspective
mchas are those who don't practice
Indian
culture which means people who don't
follow the Vic Customs that's what m
means it is not a racial term it's a
civilizational and cultural term so
there were many Indian IED Kingdoms in
Central Asia let's say 3,000 years ago
who were then classified as mchas even
the yanas the Greeks ionians were
classified as MERS what does it mean it
means that they did
not
uh they were no longer practicing Indian
customs and culture or Vic
Customs uh so even Indian origin people
who had digressed who had turned from
the Vic path were classified as mchas so
it was not about your ethnicity or your
race or the color of your skin or
whatever it was about your practices
cultural practices and if you did not
practice the Vic cultural practices or
the civilizational practices of India
then you were a MCH it wasn't about high
or low it wasn't about racial racism or
whatever it was about a certain cultural
specific
context so Greeks were were mchas from
that perspective Romans were mcha from
that perspective the Chinese who were
not practicing Vic Customs were mchas
from that perspective even Indians who
would not practice Vic Customs would be
mcha from from that perspective okay so
it's not a cultural or ethnic term it's
a civilizational
term okay aush tinglu says why has the
IND script not been deciphered and what
challenges do Scholars face in
interpreting it additionally what are
the implications for our understanding
of the Indus Valley Civilization synu
Saras civilization or phase of India
civilization if the script were
eventually
deciphered so one of the major problems
in deciphering the script is that very
we have so few
texts and the script may not even be a
script it may be pictograms so how
many pieces of script do we have written
down pieces do we have how many
inscriptional how many inscriptions do
we have at our disposal maybe 50 maybe
100 and how many characters are there
just a handful so we don't have
something like the Rosetta Stone or or
the or the bhana be inscription in which
there are entire paragraphs of text we
just have a few whatever inscriptions we
do have at our disposal it's just a few
characters which makes you wonder
whether it was a script or it was just
pictograms or it was just heraldic sign
s it is entirely possible that during
the sarasti Sindu phase of India's
civilization people may have been
writing on some form of paper or maybe
on cloth and because of India's climate
and humidity and Monsoon and all that
all that has disintegrated and what we
are seeing inscribed on these things may
actually
be
shorthand or it may be heraldic signs or
symbols and not really the script that's
one possibility the second so that is
the main reason the the it of of
evidence we have such so few of these
inscriptions that we that's one reason
why the script has not been deciphered
and some people have claimed to have
deciphered it but we don't know how true
that is what aatan mahadevan claimed to
have deciphered it I read those his his
the text in which he has claimed to deci
the script on what basis did he claim
that this means that on what there
Absolut it's entirely like you say in
Hindi
manarat entirely out of your imagination
that's what aatan mahad did his
decipherment is a joke anyway so nobody
has deciphered the text as far as we
know somebody called yadam has used
machine learning or or what was it I
don't remember I still haven't found the
time to look at it and it may be actual
decipherment and he say it Sanskrit so
the real problem is that we have so few
inscriptions and in in each of these
inscriptions there's very little text
that's the major reason now you could
use machine learning you could use
artificial intelligence to decipher it
but I guess nobody has tried that now
what if we eventually finally decipher
this text and we understand what is
written there well that will put an end
to all the theories
right so what are the theories there's
the Aran Invasion Theory there's the
Arian migration Theory there's the Arian
tourism Theory picnic Theory Arian space
Invasion Theory Alien Invasion Theory
then you have the out of India Theory
and whatnot all kinds of theories once
the Saraswati synu script is deciphered
and we can read what's written it will
be the end of all the
theories
right so that may be one of the reasons
why the script has not been deciphered
because they don't want to decipher it
because the language which the script
encodes may be very
uh what what would you say
inconvenient or the dominant
narrative so my strong hunch hunch is
that it is some form of Sanskrit maybe
vidc maybe post VC maybe late Vic
Sanskrit some form of Sanskrit that's
what I believe obviously there's no
proof of that
yet as far as I know so maybe I have to
talk to yaj and see and actually
understand what he has done
and looks like he he is onto something
but we'll see so that's what it is so
the script will put the decipherment of
the script will put a final end to all
that speculation which theory is correct
is was there an Arian space Invasion
alien invasion was there Anan picnic in
India okay name his is hidden says
please tell tell about the history of
the mag award the so-called Nobel Prize
of of Asia some so-called journalists
journalists got this so-called Nobel
Prize of Asia which made made me
question it's credibility okay the Magi
award is an American award which is
given by appr proxy Nation
Philippines okay let us see what the
what what Google and Wikipedia have to
say about this let's let's put that on
screen yes is screen is here mag
say excuse me
Ramon mag award let's go to Wikipedia
and see what Wikipedia says okay
Wikipedia is not a reliable source of
information but we can just just for the
sake of seeing it let's see what it says
it's an annual award G established to
perpetuate former Philippine president
Ramon mag is example of Integrity in
governance so apparently Ramon mag was
an example of Integrity in governance
courageous service to the people and
pragmatic realism within a Democratic
Society so it it it it seeks to
uh promote democracy Integrity in
government governance courageous service
to the people and pragmatic idealism
this prize was established in 1857 by
the trustees of the Rockefeller Brothers
fund oh based in New York City with the
concurrence of the Philippine government
the Philippine government is and was a
wasal of the US okay and the fund is uh
so the the prize money comes from the US
and
uh this has generated criticism due to
the allegations of brutal suppression of
descent and subserviency to the US
government during Max's life tenure as
defense secretary and president which
tells you that he
was an agent of the US it was the US
stouge mag say okay and the money comes
from the US so it's an American award
given via a proxy which is the
Philippines and the Americans occupied
the Philippines for a long time time
have you heard of the moro Moro Massacre
let's go to Moro
Massacre Moro
Massacre
okay uh it was about how many people did
the Americans kill in this massacre 800
900 men women
children and it was not a battle
actually it was a massacre and let's not
put that on the screen because it is not
appropriate for this live stream but
let's go back to mag award okay so the
Philippines used to be a
Hindu culture the Spaniards the Spanish
came and destroyed Hinduism they
forcibly converted lots of Filipinos to
to Catholic Christianity then the
Americans defeated the Spanish kind of
and they took over the Philippines and
and occupied the Philippines and then
Philippines eventually became soall
independent which means there was a
puppet government which served us
interests nevertheless and ma was a us
to
so that's what this award is now who are
the people who have got this
award let us
see uh enen laoa for his extraordinary
Valor in defense of Freedom
strengthening among a believe beler
people for the res the resolution to
resist tyranny which means that he
fought the Vietnamese Communists JP
Narayan was actually a good man for his
constructive articulation of a public
conscious for Modern India so during the
time when the Indian government was very
strongly Pro USSR this guy was opposing
the Indian government which is which
made him a good guy at the time who else
do we
have
uh okay CTI parna Kara for vigorously
defending the interests of Thai Farmers
critically challenging government
policies with the pragmatism of a man
who knows the soil okay so for opposing
his for for o for opposing the chakri
dynasty and doing farmer protests good
job sounds very familiar somehow huh
what else do we have and so on Bishop
somebody subul lakmi Ms subul
lakmi uh and so on Eddie Eddie
Fukuoka lots of other people who do we
have a Chinese
lady what else Del Lama
Tatu uh let's see some interesting names
shall we who else do we
have Ila but gandhian principles of
course gandan principles are very
important of
course uh so Muhammad yunus zaah
Chri uh Aruna Roy big Bindy Brigade
interesting who
else
prakash
journalism short toj Roy okay Akira
kurova uh Arun Shri that's interesting
in 1982 that's very
interesting uh let us see some
more peace oh Mother Teresa has to be
there
obviously uh what else what else what
else let us see who else do I see some
more oh do we see interesting names
here uh I wonder I wonder
look at this guy TM Krishna the Hindu
phobic classical
singer right who was in the eye of a
controversy
recently did we see any other
interesting figures anywhere I I don't
know maybe I can't see very well so the
point is it's an American award given to
people who serve American interests I
mean that's what they say it could be
maybe it's a completely innocent award
but that's what it is so it's a Philip
it's it's an award funded by the US
given VI the
Philippines and the and it's given to
people who in some way or the other
Serve American interests that that's
what many people allege I don't know I'm
a very innocent people I don't know
right what do I
know okay Malik Sayad says give some
advice as to what skills should we
learn for an 18yearold from your
experience what skills see today in
today's world the this world is changing
very rapidly with the Advent of AI your
skills are going to be you you may spend
years developing a set of skills and
tomorrow you'll find that they they
become AB
Obsolete and the Indian education system
is
so bad that it's going to make you so
badly vulnerable to technological
advances your entire skill set can be
replaced by an AI then what do you
do right
so what skills do you need to learn the
first skill is to learn how to
question don't not to
question you should be able to ask the
right questions not to others but to
yourself first of
all because asking a question means
formulating a
problem so question everything ask
questions ask questions to yourself
learn how to find information find
data find knowledge don't rely on
people's
opinions learn critical thinking but
also learn how to learn what do I mean
by that okay let's say
you know how to you've learned how to do
computer programming you've learned
Python and you've learned SQL and you
learned Ruby on Rails you learned Java
whatever whatever you've learned you're
are a full stack developer let's say and
then you find out that AI has taken over
everything and now you don't need all
this what do you do so you don't need to
learn how to learn you need to be able
to quickly learn new
skills which will keep you ahead of the
curve so the ability to learn new skills
at any age that's very
important so these are these are some of
some of the things you need
to these are some of the skills you need
to learn so the main thing is always
have an attitude of questioning things
of of
of not believing whatever you you you
told question everything learn how to to
find information learn how to use a
search engine learn how to use AI learn
how to leverage Ai and learn how to
quickly acquire new
skills that's what I would say that's
some of the things you that that if you
have that skill set then you'll be fine
long term
okay vishwas vashishta says what's your
opinion about floating nuclear power
station of Russia I think it's awesome
it's fantastic it's brilliant it's
mindboggling brilliant awesome
wonderful mind blasting that's my
opinion I know why you asked this
question you did not want my opinion you
actually wanted to understand what this
thing is about but see how you
formulated your question my point is
learn how to formulate
questions okay learn how to formulate
questions because a question is a
problem statement you are you actually
want to understand what these things are
but you ask me for my opinion so I'll
say oh it's awesome is that what you
want me to say learn how to ask
questions learn how to communicate yeah
let me go
back one second where's the
mouse yeah go back to this learn how to
communicate communication is is critical
it's crucial to everything learn how to
communicate verbally learn how to
communicate in
writing now let's go back here so what
are these floating nuclear power
stations these are nuclear power station
smallish nuclear reactors installed on
ships one of you can have I mean if you
look at the American uh aircraft
carriers they all have a nuclear reactor
on board nuclear submarines have a
nuclear reactor on board similarly these
are ships large ships with nuclear
reactors on board what's the point of
that the point of that is that Russia
where's the
map where is map I want to find map so
here is
Russia
um on the map so you can see Russia is a
very large nation and a significant
portion of Russia is up there in the
North in the Arctic Circle fren most of
the time and much of it is significantly
isolated and far away from the populous
regions in the west of Russia so much of
the much of Eurasian Russia is is is
tremendously remote so there are these
towns and cities here which may not have
good access to electricity so if you
have a floating nuclear power station
and if you have if you have a new oil
Discovery or gas Discovery or coil disc
coal Discovery or some other mineral
resource Discovery in some remote part
of Russia and you want to start
leveraging and using that but you don't
don't have access to power then you send
this floating nuclear reactor there
nuclear power station there it's going
to produce it's going to produce
electricity generate electricity and
serve as a stop Gap solution to this
problem so Russia is one nation that
that faces this problem so I think
there's a plan to build a whole bunch of
these floating po nuclear power stations
so that's what it's about it's
about giving Electric in electric power
generation capability is on demand to
remote place remote Coastal parts of
Russia that's what's it's about so yeah
I think there's only one right now I
think they have to replenish the nuclear
fuel every three years or five years I
think every three years and there are
there have been people who have raised
concerns about this because a ship a
ship can sink then it would contaminate
the ocean with possibly and you don't
want that that situation so there have
been
some some concerns raised about this but
overall that's the concept and there's
at least one in operation right now
academic something they call
it okay let's take uh a couple
questions copile says Bohemian rap CID
is it the greatest song of all time
what's your favorite song in artist uh
look I'm not that huge of fan of
Bohemian rap CID good song Mama
something Mama whatever Queen right
Fredy Mercury Faro Busara uh what's my
favorite I'm I'm I think uh Queen is
great they have some great songs one of
the great great rock bands obviously
some of the greatest live shows they did
my favorite song in artist look I
there's no one song or artist that I
have I I listen to music from everywhere
I have a very eclectic taste in music I
will listen to music from Mali where's
Mali you will ask
Mali is in Western Africa
Mali I will use I will listen to music
from Mali
aliak you may not have heard of these
people I will listen to music from
Somalia you may not have heard of Somali
music but it's actually quite similar to
Indian music in some ways I listen to
music from everywhere I have a very very
very diverse and eclectic tast in music
I listen to music from Southern America
pan
pipes uh so and uh so I don't have any I
listen to Celtic folk music Davey Graham
who was the other guy whose name I
forget there Nick Drake I will I used to
play raaga music Indian ragas on the
guitar these days I don't touch the
guitar no time so I have a very eclectic
tast in music I don't have any favorite
song any favorite artist I have a bunch
of favorite artists I have a bunch of
favorite songs a bunch of favorite
genres
I I listen to all kinds of music but if
you were to ask me about favorite
artists Queen yeah sure Queen is great
Le zeppin Pink Floyd in the doors was
also
good and so many more so many so so many
more okay next
question okay I think I'll take
questions from the live chat now I've
answered lots of questions from the
comments let us answer questions from
live
chat okay samanta says Sam
many young men voted Nota because they
were angry about with political parties
women appeasement women appeasement they
burned underwear it's a protest against
somebody since he promised for 50%
reservation okay I wasn't aware of that
but I'm not sure there's a question in
there so okay that's
interesting Russian trap is really good
okay Celtic music is great yes you know
what Celtic music is almost like Indian
Raga music and if you want to play it on
a guitar you need a dad Gad tuning D A
Gad in case you know what that is and
that music is great for certain Indian
draggers as well and if you look and
artist like Davy Graham
and who's the guy who played Anie forget
the guy's name it was DAV Graham but
somebody else as well so these guys were
deeply interested in Indian Raga music
and if you and and Celtic music sounds
very very Indian some in many ways and
it goes very well with the
tbla so yeah Celtic music is great
mayang says Mali is a Sanskrit word and
sumali who's another Sanskrit name which
became
Somalia
okay look I'm not sure that's quite how
it is but yeah in in in French in the
French language there's something called
phami phami means false friends it means
words that sound similar in two
languages but they actually have very
different meanings so let's not try to
connect everything to Sanskrit it may
not quite be the case but I I know where
you're coming from I know where you're
coming from I understand I
understand okay now what
else uh let's let's let's take some
questions other questions apurva says
where do I start initiating myself into
Indian classical music uh well depends
if you like vocal music you can listen
to beims
josi that is or you can listen to ktic
musicians m subalakshmi
Al so if you if you
like instrumental you can listen to
Sitar greats like nikil Goos like uh pit
Rish Shankar pit nikil G nikil ban sorry
nikil
benergy Nan Goos is somebody who still
plays
satar I meant nikil
benergy who else was there um obviously
ravish Shankar pit Rish Shankar who
passed away a few years ago uh there are
the the dger brothers Rajan sag Rajan
sjin
no I forget I forget now it's been so
long since I listen to all this but
there is drupad music so I would say
listen to lots of classical music listen
to the greats listen toad bismah Khan
Shai who was a Krishna Bak by the way um
vad Khan pit vad Khan I watched his I
was I was present at his last concert
nobody knew it was his last concert
because he passed away a few days later
so I was there um sod sod is nice uh
what was his
name I I forget the names obviously
amjad Khan is still amjad Ali Khan is
still alive but who was the
guy okay that guy also I watched his
last concert it was so weird so anyway
my point is listen to lots of this it's
beautiful it's
brilliant listen to various ragas
familiar yourself familiar
familiarize yourself with ragas if you
like the flute listen to panalal Goos
listen to Har Prasad jasia so much you
can do Indian classical music is so
incredibly rich and diverse it is the
greatest musical tradition in the
history of humanity but we don't know
about it because your God damned
education system will not tell you a
word about it the greatest one of the
greatest intellectual achievements of
humankind of mankind is Indian classical
music the Great greatest musical system
ever
ever Western scales and Melodies and
harmonies are nothing compared to a Raga
a Raga has a character and a personality
of its own it has rigid rules but almost
infinite scope for experimentation
within those those boundaries it's
incredible but you don't no one knows
these things it's it's so sad how how
Indian culture is dying
and that's one of my criticisms one of
my frustrations when it comes to the
government of India they should do more
about culture of course they've done so
much for the upliftment of the country
Mr Modi has done tremendous amounts of
work the best prime minister since 1947
Mr Modi but I am seriously frustrated
about the lack of action when it comes
to culture civilization and education
and illegal immigration there are
Ministries for this so I hope this this
progress on this
front okay oh yes anmol says the
Bangladesh BM was right Mrs Miss H Shina
Sinister plans are aood to create a
Christian state of zoor people in
in in West in the far east region of
India so the Americans want to create a
Christian Nation in this region okay the
Manipur crisis is a geopolitical crisis
and behind it is the West they actually
told shik Hina that we will not
interfere in the Bangladesh elections if
you give us an island that the Americans
want and you allow us to create a
Christian Nation in a certain part of
Bangladesh give the cookies a nation of
their own the cookies are fighting three
countries right now India Bangladesh and
Burma okay and this is a geopolitical
issue so the Manipur problem right now
it has no immediate
solution so yeah she actually has blown
the lid of this and I really appreciate
that and it's a very courageous thing
that she has done
shik geopolitical dub says when will we
see the statue of naaji being installed
in European countries how long will he
we have to sell Gandhi's name in Europe
I don't see we will ever see subash
Chandra bosz's statues being installed
in Europe that won't
happen Mr Gandhi well he that's a brand
that has been created over time and it
it represents a weak nonviolent India
and that is something the whole world
especially the Western world would world
would like to see that's why they they
would like to honor Gandhi Mr Gandhi
because that's the the values they want
India to practice today that's the path
they want India to walk today and the
government of India over the past 70
years has invested so much into building
this brand that it just continues and
today the problem is if you criticize Mr
Gandhi you're going to get a tremendous
amount of hate and if you're a
politician you simply can't afford to
criticize Mr Gandhi even today because
the majority of Indians are brainwashed
because of the education system it all
goes back to the goddamned education
system and how bad it is that's why we
need to start reforming it
fundamentally but yeah uh we won't see
statues of Mr Bose being installed
anywhere won't
happen miir says what do you think about
a small African country like mozambik I
think it's fantastic it's brilliant it's
mind-blowing it's
awesome I'm sure that's not what you
want me to say right so you have to ask
a specific
question I don't know what you're asking
what do I think about it I think it's
awesome brilliant it's
beautiful wonderful vibrant African
culture awesome mind-blowing I don't
know what you want me to answer what do
you want me to say what do I think about
their economy what do I think about
their history what do I think about
their geopolitics
ask a specific
question understand learn how to ask
question formulate questions the right
way you asked a very generic question to
which I can give a very generic answer
look mozic if you want to see where it
is we can Discover it let's go back to
the
map let me actually uh speak a little
bit about mozambik so mozambik is this
nation in Eastern Africa it has
connections historic ancient connections
with India if if you see if you see the
kind of clothes the people of mozambik
Tanzania Kenya wear those Fabrics those
patterns are reminiscent of the clothes
people in Gujarat used to wear in the
19th even 20th century even now if you
see the cuisine in mozambik in Tanzania
in Kenya it's very very strongly
influenced by India these countries uh
there's a significant Islamic population
in these countries these countries are
very poor and most of these countries
are resource Rich so I can give you
information I can answer the question
but only if you ask me a specific
question will will I be to able to
actually tell you
something okay
um uh herel says uh did the Deep State
focus on Indian elections too much uh
that now they are losing their
stronghold Europe recently I think right
parties got huge gains in the European
Parliament EU Parliament now the US has
the resource has sufficient resources to
focus on multiple countries at the same
time they have the resources to do that
so it's not like if they focus on
influencing the Indian election and
interfering in the Indian election then
they will not be able to focus on
anything else it's not like that they
have the resources to interfere in half
the world's elections at the same time
but what's happening in Europe that the
rightwing like M Senora milone part Sor
Sorina mone's party and so on Madame
mone's party Etc and the Netherlands
also other places the right wing you can
see what they call the far right is
enjoying a kind of resurgence in Europe
it's simply a natural reaction to the
policies of the EU government of the EU
which are deeply deeply anti- people
policies it's about bringing in illegal
immigration into Europe only military
age men from certain countries and who
belong to certain religions that's what
is being done to Europe it is
artificially re-engineering European
demographics cultural
demographics ethnic demographics and
religious demographics they are trying
to destroy Europe to destroy Europe's
identity that's why you will have some
kind of a reaction and you're seeing
that right now so this doesn't have any
connection with the American attempts to
interfere within India which have
happened in 2024 which will happen in
the future which have happened in the
past as well not
connected
uh fakaza father of akaza says your
opinions on Peter the Great I think he
was
great was fantastic mind-blowing
brilliant awesome super
awesome look uh this is okay so look
Peter the Great is a very interesting
figure and uh it would take me a certain
amount of time to give you an overview
of this guy and his career and his
impact on the world so maybe we can do
it in the next live stream right now
I'll just take rapid fire questions but
okay let's maybe you can reformulate
this question in a slightly better way
for the next live stream whenever it
happens and I can take it
up
uh Saran s says if the Americans are the
descendants of the British why did
theight them and call it the war of
independence yeah interesting question
right
so when you have an entire continent of
your own then why would you send 2%
taxes to the king of
England you would like to keep the 2%
also for yourself so it was not about
fighting look the Mahabharat was cousins
fighting cousins
okay so ethnicity has nothing to do
about this it is about personal
interest so they fought them because
they wanted the entire continent for
themselves George Washington and his
cronies right it was simply about greed
and about keeping all the money for
yourself 2% was too much for them to
give as a tax to the British and today
the Americans pay what 45% tax and they
keep quiet about it and they went to war
for 2% how's that
akilesh says if you could design a new
constitution for India what core
principles would guide it it would be a
dharmic constitution as simple as that
that's the core principle The Core
principle is Dharma Dharma the
constitution of India has to be a
dharmic constitution not an adharmic
Constitution the way we what we have
today and it has to be ratified by the
people of India the current Constitution
has never been ratified by the people of
India
okay Malik said says even if you look at
satellite images of cities of countries
like IR like Iraq Syria Etc they look
planned and well organized why is that
and why is a random Indian city look why
does it look messy without even having a
war it's because of the way India was
governed after 1947 if you look at you
go to the places where the British have
had if you look at various cities that
the British have
governed take
uh let's not talk about India for for
for just a bit let's go to the
map and let me show you a city that the
British governed
okay which is rangun Yangon now let's
take a look at Yangon
so
um so there are parts of yon that uh the
British
governed okay I guess it will take me a
while what about old young or
British British school British
University College or something
so there will be parts of Yangon that
were uh developed by the British which
will be much better organized than later
Young on similarly there will be certain
Indian cities which the British actually
built and developed and those Indian
cities those parts of those Indian
cities will be will be laid out properly
very well structured and the the same
city the areas that developed after 1947
will be all half-hazard and chaotic why
is that it's because after 1947 the
Indian governments did not care about
the people they did not PL cities they
were more interested in in extracting
resources out of out of the people
through corruption and other means and
cities just developed completely
randomly and organically without any
planning whatsoever and of course in in
like I said in many hypothetical cities
in India the the local politics ations
have hypothetically allowed large slums
to come up they've actually put those
slums in place so that the these slums
in which foreign infiltrators live they
can serve as vote Banks because those
foreign infiltrators will be given
Indian Indian papers
documents it's the root cause is
corruption the root cause is government
apathy India has way more resources than
the Nations you've named Syria Iraq
whatever but how are the resources used
where do those resources go who Pockets
those those resources even today
in the hypothetical
municipalities and District organiz
district uh things of various Indian
cities
right biml says I'm a Nepali Hindu I
want the Vic V flourish in the Indian
subcontinent including Nepal but I
foresee the loss a loss of napales
identity within it which we do not want
I know you are right those fears are
well Justified after the earthquake the
ma recent major earthquake in Nepal you
know there were many buildings that that
were brought down by the earthquake that
were destroyed many temples got damaged
and I saw on the on social media many
missionaries saying that it is good that
these temples have been destroyed by the
earthquakes now we should have churches
coming up over there and after the CH
after the earthquake there has been a
major focus on Nepal from the missionary
uh organizations
and lots of nepales are being converted
to foreign religions that's happening
that's one thing that's happening and
secondly we have the Communist
governments that are communist parties
that that holds way Nepal and they are
also many of them are also very badly
hinduphobic so it looks like Nepal will
Al also go go down the same route of
secularism and hinduphobia looks like
that and obviously there is a reaction
to that as well which means that there
are there are there's a section of
society in Nepal that wants a return to
Hindu Raj Tantra Hindu
monarchy now who prevails right now the
politicians the the the Communist
politicians are in
power and so they will want to retain
their power cling cling on to power and
they will not allow this to happen So
eventually we'll have to see whether the
people Prevail or whether the people are
reduced to a minority and most people
become get converted to foreign
religions I hope it doesn't happen I
would like to see Nepal return to its
roots which is the same Roots as India
as bhat which is the civilizational
identity that has always been the Nepali
civilizational identity which is the
same as the Bara civilizational
identity okay
anov Jane says what's your thought on
vac vac ramaswami is VP I don't think he
could become VP maybe it'll be somebody
else but he if Mr Trump does win this
election the upcoming election then v
may possibly get a good position in his
cabinet I don't think he'll be the vice
president I don't think
so will he be a good vice president if
he hypothetically becomes the VP I don't
know I think what V needs to do is to
get some proper experience of a few few
years in a proper leadership leadership
position governance position and he has
to prove his worth then people will take
him more seriously and then maybe in 29
he could be VP or maybe even run for
president I think is a very good speaker
is's a tremendously intelligent person
but one his one weakness is that he
doesn't have any actual experience
leading and governing so he needs to get
that experience gain that experience
he's never been the governor of a state
or even the mayor of a city for example
you need something right some
demonstrable proof of your actual
abilities so he lacks that so maybe if
Trump does win then maybe VI will get a
good position in the cabinet and that
would be the stepping stone for him to
move forward to 2029 but Will trump win
is the big question I think it's
unlikely I of course could be wrong but
I think it's unlikely that Trump will
win so that's the next question by Yash
is there any chance for Trump to come to
power in the US what would be more
favorable for India Biden coming to
power or Trump look Biden I don't see
him coming to power I don't see him
standing for election in 20 in in 24
he's way way way past his expiry date as
as a functioning human being he belongs
in a retirement home in an elderly home
he is cognitively impaired it's very CLE
here so Biden if they tried I mean the
Democrats could very well put Biden up
for for president again who
knows the real question is is there any
chance of trump coming back to
Power I think I would be happy to see
him come back to Power because I think
the US will be a much more interesting
place with him in power but will he
actually come to power I think it's
unlikely I think uh if the elections are
free and fair he may sweep the elections
but I think it's unlikely that he'll
come to power let's just put it at that
and I think he'll be lucky if he is not
1963 so I could be wrong but I don't
think he could come back to he'll come
back to
Power okay we are almost there almost at
the
end Malik said says why don't you Vlog
look I'm not a
vlogger for for for vlogging you need to
spend the day recording yourself then
you edit the whole thing down to a 10 15
minute thing that's not for
me uh I could perhaps do it when I
travel someplace but then again then
again you can't experience what you're
doing because you're busy busy filming
yourself and maybe you're not filming it
yourself maybe you have somebody else do
it for you but then you're on camera and
well that's different as opposed to when
you're not on camera so that's not for
me but I do these live streams which is
me being 100% authentic and unfiltered
so consider these to be
Vlogs uh this is more authentic than
being a being a vlogger because when
you're doing these two hour live streams
there's not you can't hide who you are
you simply can't hide who you really are
your authentic self will come through in
a vlog you can act you can edit stuff
you can censor stuff if you if you if
you make a slip or a mistake but in a
live stream you can't do that so I think
live streams are way more authentic than
Vlogs Vlogs can perhaps be more be more
entertaining you can have transitions
you can have wonderful highlights you
can have music you can have acting you
can play a character and people will
believe it's the real thing but a vlog
is not the real thing I I'm sure it's
more entertaining but a live stream is
where you get to see the real the person
who they really are I mean I've done
what this is live stream 189 you know
the real me after doing 189 live
streams if if if I was pretending to be
somebody I'm not you can't do it for 189
episodes you simply can't so you were
seeing the authentic me I mean that's
the difference between a live stream and
a vlog so yeah so Vlogs I may do some
Vlogs in the future maybe but overall
I'm not a vlogger I'm more of what do
you see
okay so shall we take maybe one or two
questions okay Dr Jay Shankar says do
you see previous term ministers
retaining their Ministries how do you
see previous term ministers retaining
their Ministries uh I don't know I'm not
a political expert when it comes to
internal politics I think at least some
of them could retain their Ministries I
predict that Dr J Shankar Dr J Shankar
will retain his ministry external
Affairs I I predict that right now let's
see how how true that comes out to be I
don't think he'll be given defense or
Finance I think he will be foreign
minister so he will for sure rain the
ministry who whether Mrs SI Raman
retains Finance or goes to some other
Ministry and so on I'm not sure about
that but one prediction I can certainly
make others I think some of them will
certainly retain the Ministries some of
of them will be reshuffled but Dr J
Shankar will remain foreign minister
that is my
prediction okay I think here we are okay
let's take one or two more questions uh
shall
we how fast are you able to read books
and how I think I read books at the
speed of light or something I read
really really fast I can actually
probably digest a paragraph in a couple
of second seconds or something depending
on the context depending on the topic if
it's a completely new topic for me it
may take longer if I'm reading fiction I
just Breeze through
books uh if I'm reading non-fiction and
it's something subject I'm more familiar
with I could read really really fast so
the more you read the better you get and
the faster you get and I've read I don't
know tens of thousands of books perhaps
so how to practice
okay Sonia sin says thank you for your
authenticity thank you so much
appreciate
it okay
okay ad says how to improve English you
improve English or Hindi or asames or
Thai or sili or any language the way you
improve your guitar skills your football
skills your boxing skills or whatever by
practice practice practice practice you
want improve your English by reading
books but look actually you can at least
your comprehension of English will
improve if you read lots of books but if
you want to be able to speak better
speak speak speak speak all day all
night
and and try and catch where you're
deficient and improve on that best thing
is record yourself with your phone 10
minutes a day speaking something and
then force yourself to watch that and
you won't enjoy that experience but
that's what's going to help you improve
help you see where you need to improve
that goes to public speaking to English
Hindi whatever that's how you improve by
consciously improving
regularly make a 1% Improvement every
week not every day just every week that
itself is a is the way to do it okay my
friends I think we are done we are at
the end of this session 2 hours 14 plus
minutes thank you very much once again
for all your questions this has been a
hybrid session I can see Magnus Carlson
and Empress re and others asking
questions very very very sorry I'm going
to be able to I'm not going to be able
to take your questions now but we will
continue this in the next in the future
live streams one coming up very soon all
right thank you so much for all the
questions for your viewership for your
support for everything and I will see
you very soon in the next live stream
and always as always don't forget to
keep raising your standards see you bye